welcome to my review of the 16 inch
MacBook Pro with the M1 Max chip as you
know when Apple announced the new M1
MacBooks I didn't immediately buy one
because I always like to wait and see if
there is a problem with the new version
of anything and I also wanted to wait
and see if something more powerful
showed up later and I am very very happy
I waited because this thing is an
absolute Beast I've been using this for
more than six months now and I want to
share with you the good parts the bad
parts and who do I think should buy this
starting with the good parts the speed
on this thing is insane my programs
compile two to three times faster
compared to the Intel MacBook Pro this
really hit me when I was recording the
free react native course I was running
iOS simulator Android simulator vs code
the browser and I was also recording my
screen recording the camera and the
microphone all those things combined
usually the Intel MacBook Pro had
problems with this it became very warm
the fan became very noisy and the cleats
weren't Snappy it was very laggy now
nothing really crashed and nothing
really stopped working but it was laggy
it was just slow sometimes they even the
video quality dropped now compare that
with this thing right here this the M1
Max
crazy insane I can run the i o simulator
Android simulator browser vs code record
my camera record my screen recording
audio all those things is like if it
wasn't doing any work at all I can
barely hear the fan it doesn't get warm
it's crazy it the clicks are still
Snappy the video quality is great it's
unbelievable how good this thing is the
thing that impressed me the most and the
thing that I love the most about this
laptop isn't actually the speed because
we all knew that M1 was faster than
Intel now the thing that I really really
didn't expect but I absolutely love is
the battery life it lasts so long it's
crazy when I'm doing any programming
related tasks it can last for the whole
day not even going down to the 70
percent it's crazy there was a day when
I first noticed this when I didn't want
to work on my desk and instead I want to
work on my sofa so I charged the laptop
800 and went and worked on the sofa for
the whole day at least six to seven
hours I was doing Docker I was running
vs code I was compiling some stuff I was
also running the browser watching some
video so video playback and I was
running some electron applications that
as we know electron takes a lot of
memory and Battery like for example
slack and maybe figma or Spotify now
after six seven hours of this I looked
at the battery and I see that it was in
the high 60 almost 70 something percent
and that was after six seven or even
eight hours of work it didn't drop that
much I was so so surprised if that was
my Intel MacBook Pro I am sure the
battery wouldn't have lost that much or
at least it will be in the low 20s or
the low 10 percent now of course we
could say that this is because the
battery as well is new this is true the
internet good Pro doesn't have a new
battery so that's also something to
consider but still I can really feel how
having the M1 Max chip is better for
Apple because now they can optimize so
much that they require less power it's
insane onto the bad parts now I don't
really have anything bad to say about
the hardware of this laptop it's good
quality Apple builds good quality stuff
but what I have to say is that I found
some software crashing a lot sometimes
um yeah just crashed in the M1 just
things just crashed it crashed more
often than on the Intel MacBook Pro but
I have to say that it is getting better
these are just bugs and developers are
going to fix the box as the time passes
for example when I started using this
the first time for I think two weeks
Brave browser crashed at least once a
day it was really really annoying of
course it wasn't happening on the
internet it was something very specific
to the M1 but now it's fine so it's just
as time passes things just get better
with tech what really annoyed me was how
long it took me to get like my Dev setup
ready like in the Intel it didn't take
me that long to get my compilers my
simulators my virtual machines ready in
the M1 Book Pro it took me longer some
things like some python stuff it wasn't
able to be installed it just wouldn't
work so I had to use Docker for that it
was kind of annoying but it's not a big
deal and again it might get better with
time as people Port their libraries and
their software to the M1 chips another
cool thing about this laptop is of
course how many ports it has it doesn't
have a useless touch bar and the
keyboard is really really good but this
is not something to celebrate this
should be the minimum requirement for a
laptop with this price tag the reason
why I'm happy about all the ports and
the keyboard and everything is because I
had to buy the 2016 Intel MacBook Pro
which was garbage personally it didn't
have ports the keyword was really bad it
had a really useless touch bar so now
I'm glad we went back to the bare
minimum so I'm gonna celebrate that I'm
not going to compliment apple on that
it's not Innovation it's the bare
minimum for something with this price
tag so now the last question is who do I
think should buy this machine who is the
target audience for this and I
personally think that developers are not
the target audience for this machine
this is way too powerful I think this is
going to shine in the hands of an
architect that has to do 3D renders or
maybe maybe a developer working with
Unreal Engine having to load very heavy
3D scenes maybe somebody doing a lot of
graphic design with blender or I don't
know some really heavy graphic stuff I
don't think that developers need all
this power maybe the battery life is
amazing that is for sure but it's very
expensive and the power is not something
that developers can really harness in a
way I think if we're just doing
programming tasks like writing code
compiling stuff installing some packages
browsing the web and watching videos I
don't really think
we need something like this personally
personally if I didn't make courses if I
didn't render videos and edit videos and
do all those things I don't think I
would have bought this or at least I
wouldn't have maxed it out as much as I
did but that's just what I think if you
have the money and you want to Splash on
something like this then of course go
ahead it is a good machine it is
incredibly fast and the battery is
amazing and also if you are curious and
you want to check out the courses that I
recorded on this machine and on the
Intel machine then please click the link
below because there you will find free
courses on JavaScript python go react
react native redox graphql Apollo
nesters next year is among many other
things thank you as always for watching
let me know what you think about my
review this is the first time I do any
sort of tech review in this channel so I
apologize if it's not what you were
expecting I don't know how to do reviews
and I don't watch review channels so
this is as good as it gets let me know
in the comments also if you purchase one
of these are you happy with it are you
gonna take it back what do you think
about the other ones the you buy the M2
should we buy them too because I've seen
some people having problems with it let
me know in the comments I'm going to be
looking at them right now as always stay
free stay happy